Emilio Campos Jr.

(815) 543-8461 | ecampos.jr54@gmail.com | Chicago, IL (Open to relocation) | LinkedIn | GitHub

Junior Software Engineer

I am a software engineering student learning Javascript, React and Python. I am well prepared to succeed as a software engineer based on my experience as an attorney where I handled up to 60 cases at once, independently and as part of a small team.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Javascript + HTML + CSS + MongoDB + Express + Node + React Problem Solving + Attention to Detail + Exceptional verbal and written communication skills

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Emilio's Blackjack - https://3campos.github.io/Project-1/ | Javascript | HTML | CSS |

My take on the classic card game, using a 52-card deck. I typed 3,000 lines of code consisting of multiple functions to facilitate random dealing and play.

$Ollivanders - \underline{https://ollivanders-wands-app-ec.herokuapp.com/} \ | \ Javascript \ | \ HTML \ | \ CSS \ | \ MongoDB \ | \ Express \ | \ Node \ |$

I built an inventory of wands from the viewpoint of Ollivander of the Harry Potter series. I added styling to make it appear magical, including light-blue shadowing for cards in the inventory and a levitation effect on the wands.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Staff Attorney I | Catholic Charities Legal Assistance

June 2021 - April 2022

- Advised over 100 clients' on their legal rights and advocated for them in court to reach favorable results
- Negotiated with multiple opposing counsels to reach optimal case resolution for clients

Attorney at Law | Bryce Downey and Lenkov LLC

January 2021 - June 2021

- Litigated cases through settlement or trial including serving as sole attorney at trial and in negotiations
- Drafted legal analyses based on accident compensability, extent of medical treatment, and progressively evaluated trial exposure and settlement valuation of cases
- Argued for favorable trial exposure and settlement valuation by an arbitrator at pretrial hearings

Law Clerk

January 2020 - June 2020 & October. 2020 - January 2021

- Drafted multiple motions to dismiss and prepared exhibits
- Reviewed file materials to draft multiple lump sum settlement contracts and calculated damages

Paralegal

March 2016 - August 2017

• Routinely analyzed hundreds of pages of medical records to draft concise summaries for expert physicians

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly | Remote

May 2022 - November 2022

An intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

University of Illinois College of Law

May 2020

Juris Doctor

Latino Law Students Association: Treasurer; Alumni Scholarship Committee Delegate

Illinois Student Government: Senator for the College of Law (2018-2019)

Loyola University Chicago

May 2013

Bachelor's of Business of Administration in Economics and Bachelor's of Business of Administration in Business Management